Guide to the Stanley C. Marshall Papers, 1944-2005 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Stanley C. Marshall papers 1944-2005 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Marshall, Stanley C.
17.5 linear feet Extent: 11625 Items
Stanley C. Marshall was a pioneer in the field of strategic market planning, and an educator, lecturer, and humanitarian. The Stanley C. Marshall Papers span the years 1944-2005 and include client files, speeches and presentations, publications, correspondence, advertising and civic awards, photographs, slides, audiocassettes and audiotapes, videocassettes and videotapes, motion picture film reels, and digital audio tape that document Marshall's career as a strategic marketing planner and consultant, as well as his involvement with humanitarian projects. The collection reflects Marshall's work for advertising and marketing firms, including Lando, Marsteller Advertising, and his own company, Stanley Marshall, Inc. Client files include 3M, Black Box, Delta Dental Plan, General Electric, International Management Center, PPG, Pure Industries (Stackpole), Scott Fetzer (Berkshire Hathaway), Sony, United Jewish Foundation, and Westinghouse. Also documented are Marshall's activities with public service and educational organizations that include UNICEF, the Conflict Resolution Center, the Negro Educational Emergency Drive (NEED, a project of the Urban League of Pittsburgh), the Network of International Business Schools (NIBS), and the Penn Technical Institute (a junior college, now part of the Pittsburgh Technical Institute). A significant portion of the files relate to businesses and institutions in the Pittsburgh, Pa., area.
RL.00851
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Use copies are available in the collection.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Stanley C. Marshall Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2005.
Biographical Note
1919 Born, New York, NY.
1943 B.S., Electrical Engineering, Bucknell University
1943-1945 Test Engineer, General Electric
1945-1950 Sales Promotions Manager and Editor of Technical Publications, Sauerman Brothers, Chicago, Ill. Account Executive, Promotions, Inc., Chicago, Ill.
1946-1947 Graduate program, Television and Industrial Engineering, Illinois Institute of Technology
1950 Assistant to the Director, Penn Technical Institute
1952 President and Director, Lando, Inc.
1967 Director and President, Pittsburgh Commerce Institute Director, Partnership for Productivity Foundation
1973 Director, Friends of Publishing Company
1977-1983 Member, Pennsylvania Board of Education
1978 Vice President and General Manager of Marstellar Inc.'s Pittsburgh office
1979 President, Stanley C. Marshall, Inc.
1984 President, USA NOW, Inc.
1985 Member, Academy of Independent Scholars
2000 Elected to the Pittsburgh Advertising Federation Hall of Fame
2005 Died
During his career, Marshall held the rank of Adjunct Professor at the Katz School of Business at the University of Pittsburgh. Marshall also lectured at Boston University, Carnegie-Mellon University, Duquesne University, in the United Kingdom, Poland, and Hungary, as well as the US Department of Commerce, UNICEF, and the American Management Association.
Collection Overview
The Stanley C. Marshall Papers span the years 1944-2005 and include client files, speeches and presentations, publications, correspondence, advertising and civic awards, photographs, slides, audiocassettes and audiotapes, videocassettes and videotapes, motion picture film reels, and digital audio tape that document Marshall's career as a strategic marketing planner and consultant, as well as his involvement with humanitarian projects. The collection reflects Marshall's work for advertising and marketing firms, including Lando, Marsteller Advertising, and his own company, Stanley Marshall, Inc. Clients include 3M, Black Box, Delta Dental Plan, General Electric, International Management Center, PPG, Pure Industries (Stackpole), Scott Fetzer (Berkshire Hathaway), Sony, United Jewish Foundation, and Westinghouse. Also documented are Marshall's activities with public service and educational organizations that include UNICEF, the Conflict Resolution Center, the Negro Educational Emergency Drive (NEED, a project of the Urban League of Pittsburgh), the Network of International Business Schools (NIBS), and the Penn Technical Institute (a junior college, now part of the Pittsburgh Technical Institute). A significant portion of the files relate to businesses and institutions in the Pittsburgh, Pa., area.
The collection is organized into four series: Personal Files, Client Files, Professional Files, and Audiovisual Materials.
Subject Headings
Marshall, Stanley C.; Advertising -- History; Advertising -- Awards; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- Pennsylvania; Advertising executives; Advertising executives -- United States; African Americans -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Child care -- United States; Child welfare; Children (International law); Conflict management; Humanitarian assistance; Marketing -- United States; Marketing -- United States -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Marketing consultants -- United States; Marketing consultants -- United States -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Economic conditions; 3M Company; Berkshire Hathaway Inc.; Black Box Corporation; Conflict Resolution Center International; Delta Dental (Organization); General Electric Company; International Management Center; Lando, Inc.; Marstellar Advertising; PPG Industries; Pittsburgh Technical Institute; Sony Corporation; Stanley Marshall Inc.; UNICEF; United Jewish Foundation; Urban League of Pittsburgh; Westinghouse Electric Corporation; Photographs; Slides; Speeches; Audiocassettes; Audiotapes; Digital audio tapes; Machine-readable records; Master copies; Motion pictures; Videocassettes; Pittsburgh (Pa.); John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Additional information on advertising and marketing in the Pittsburgh, Pa., region may be found in the John E. Brennan Outdoor Advertising Surveys and the Outdoor Advertising Association of America Slide Library. Additional information on companies and institutions documented in this collection may be found in the Brouillard Communications, Inc., Records (General Electric, 3M), the D'Arcy Masius Benton & Bowles Archives (UNICEF), the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) Account Files (PPG Industries), the JWT John Devine Papers (PPG Industries), the JWT Edgar Hatcher Papers (General Electric), the JWT Advertising Vertical Files (Marsteller), and the JWT Corporation Vertical Files (General Electric).
Contents of Collection
- Client Files Series, 1965-2004 and undated, (11 boxes)
  Consists of strategic plans created for clients of Marshall, as well as correspondence and notes. Arranged alphabetically.
  - 3M, 1974-1974, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Allegheny Ludlum, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Arco Chemical, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Young Corporation, 1980-1981, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Benshaw, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Black Box Corporation, 1988-1989, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Bell Advertising, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Blue Cross of Western Pennsylvania, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Cardello, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Ciscorp, 1996-1998 (Box 2)
  - Cohen and Grigsby, 1995-1998, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Community College of Allegheny County, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Conair, 1980s and undated, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Conflict Resolution Center, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Construction Industry Advancement Program (CIAP) of Western Pennsylvania, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Cutler/Hammer, 2001-2003 (Box 2)
  - DDF & M, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Delta Dental, 1996-2003, (1-3 of 7 folders) (Box 2)
  - Delta Dental, 1996-2003 (continued), (4-7 of 7 folders) (Box 3)
  - Department of Energy, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Downtown Pittsburgh Hotels, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Disston, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Duquesne Brewing Company, 1966-1967 (Box 3)
  - Duquesne Lighting Company, 1987-1988, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Elco, 1974, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Eldervision, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Eriez, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Fox Grocery, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Friends Extension Company, 1982 (Box 3)
  - General Nutrition, 1981 (Box 3)
  - General Planning, 1995 and 2003, (1 of 2 folders) (Box 3)
  - General Planning, 1995 and 2003 (continued), (2 of 2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Gilspur, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Halstead and Mitchell, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Heartstone, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Helium Centennial, 1967 and undated, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Home Care Plus, 1993-1996 (Box 4)
  - Homewood Products, 1997-2002 (Box 4)
  - Indiana Society of Communication Strategists, 1987 and undated (Box 4)
  - Integrated Marketing, 2003 and undated (Box 4)
  - Janssen, undated (Box 4)
  - Legal Services Corporation, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Lewis and Sargent, 1997-2004 (Box 4)
  - Lodge and Shipley, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Magnetics, 1981 and undated, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Mastery Center, undated (Box 4)
  - Mobay and Molytek, 1967 and 1987 (Box 4)
  - North America Phillips, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Off Shore Power (OSP), 1973 (Box 5)
  - Oxford Film, 1968 (Box 5)
  - Partnership for Productivity (PfP), 1972 and 1981-1982, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - PGA, 1994-1995 (Box 5)
  - Phillips Conservatory, 1996 and undated (Box 5)
  - Pittsburgh/Allegheny County Tourism Advisory Board, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Pittsburgh Ballet Company, 1981-2001 and undated, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Pittsburgh Board of Education, 1975-1976, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Pittsburgh Convention Center, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Pittsburgh Dance Council, 1988 (Box 5)
  - Pittsburgh Downtown Partnership, 2003 (Box 5)
  - Pittsburgh High Tech, 1988 (Box 5)
  - Pittsburgh International Initiative of Western Pennsylvania, 1991 (Box 5)
  - Pittsburgh Regional Alliance, 1999 and 2002 (Box 5)
  - Pittsburgh Telephone Association, 2000 (Box 5)
  - PPG, 1979 and undated, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Preservation Technologies, 1996-1997 and undated (Box 5)
  - Pure Industries, 1980-1987 and undated, (4 folders) (Box 5)
  - Recycling Services, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Reed, Smith, Shaw, and McCay, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Robert Pierre Johnson Housing, 1993 (Box 6)
  - RPS, 1996-1999 (Box 6)
  - Roth Rug, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Rust, undated (Box 6)
  - Scott Fetzer Company (subsidiary of Berkshire Hathaway)
    - France, 2000-2001, (3 folders) (Box 6)
    - Park Bench, 2003-2004, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Society of Plastic Industries, undated (Box 6)
  - Sony, 1989, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Southwest Pennsylvania Industrial Resource Center, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Stackpole, 1986-1994 and undated, (4 folders) (Box 7)
  - Storms Advisory, 1997 (Box 7)
  - Strawberry Fields, 1977, 1982, and undated (Box 7)
  - Sure Trip, 1997 and undated, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Syntax, 1983, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Thermo King, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival, 1989-1991 (Box 7)
  - Tribon, 1998 (Box 7)
  - United Jewish Federation, 1996 and undated, (1-3 of 5 folders) (Box 7)
  - United Jewish Federation, 1996 and undated (continued), (4-5 of 5 folders) (Box 8)
  - Universal-Rundle, 1973 (Box 8)
  - University of Miami, 1974 (Box 8)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1994 (Box 8)
  - U.S. Department of Commerce, 1971 (Box 8)
  - U.S. Steel, 1967 and 1983 (Box 8)
  - Verosol, 1982 and undated (Box 8)
  - Voltmeter, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Wambes, 1984, (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Waterbury-Farrel, 1972, (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Welded Steel Tube, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Westinghouse
    - Advanced Projects, 1984-1985, (1-2 of 3 folders) (Box 8)
    - Advanced Projects, 1984-1985 (continued), (3 of 3 folders) (Box 9)
    - Air Brake, 1965 and undated (Box 9)
    - Communications, 1981 and undated, (3 folders) (Box 9)
    - Corporate Marketing, 1984, (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Defense, undated (Box 9)
    - ESSD (Electrical Services Division), 1980s-1990s and undated, (1-7 of 11 folders) (Box 9)
    - ESSD, 1980s-1990s and undated (continued), (8-11 of 11 folders) (Box 10)
    - Evantage, 1997 and undated (Box 10)
    - Finance, 1983 (Box 10)
    - Heavy Motor, 1988, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Lamp Division, 1980-1981 (Box 10)
    - Learning Center, 1979 (Box 10)
    - Marketing Module, undated, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Middle East, 1982, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Motor Division, 1996-1997 and undated (Box 10)
    - Public Relations, undated (Box 11)
    - Quality Evaluation, undated, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Semi Conductors, 1981 (Box 11)
    - TECO, 1997 (Box 11)
  - Wolverine Toy Company, 1979-1980 (Box 11)
  - Xerox, 1992 (Box 11)
- Personal Files Series, 1952-2005 and undated, (7 boxes)
  Includes correspondence and literature, awards and honors, and other ephemera from Marshall's personal philanthropic work. Series is organized into 3 subseries: Civic Work, Honors and Memorabilia, and Photographs.
  - Civic Work Subseries, 1970-2002 and undated
    Includes letters, fliers, and promotional materials that document Marshall's work with public service and educational institutions.
    - African American Chamber of Commerce, 2002 and undated (Box 11)
    - Career Education, 1995-1996 and undated (Box 11)
    - Conflict Resolution Center, 1984-1996 and undated (Box 11)
    - International Management Center, 1990 and 1992, (3 folders) (Box 11)
    - Marketing Education in Czechoslovakia, 1992 (Box 11)
    - Matthews Historical Society, undated (Box 11)
    - Mt. Lebanon, 2000 and undated (Box 11)
    - Negro Emergency Educational Drive (N.E.E.D), 1992-2001 and undated, (3 folders) (Box 11)
      [Project initiated in 1963 by the Urban League of Pittsburgh, to raise tuition money for college-bound low-income African Americans living in the Pittsburgh-Western Pennsylvania region.]
    - Outreach South, undated (Box 11)
    - Penn Tech, 1985 (Box 11)
    - Partnership for Productivity (PfP), undated (Box 11)
      [Organization founded in 1970 to promote and teach small business management skills in the developing world, beginning in Kenya.]
    - Pittsburgh History and Landmarks Foundation, 2002 (Box 11)
    - University of Pittsburgh Corporate Marketing Advisory Council, 1993-1994 (Box 12)
    - UNICEF, 1970 and undated (Box 12)
    - USA NOW, 1984 and undated (Box 12)
  - Honors and Memorabilia Subseries, 1966-1991 and undated
    Includes awards, plaques, and other memorabilia received by Marshall during his career.
    - Certificates of appreciation, (3 folders) (Box 12)
      [Includes certificates from the Allegheny County chapter of the American Marketing Association; Association of National Advertisers; Business and Professional Advertising Association (BPAA); Delta Dental Plan; Mt. Lebanon Magazine; PfP; and the Public Relations Association of America.]
    - Memorabilia, plaques and other awards
      - Advertising Agency Executive of the Year, BPAA Pittsburgh, 1977 (Box 12)
      - Anniversary plaque from Joan and Al Dudreck, 1989 (Box 12)
      - Jaycees, Man of the Year, 1966 (Box 12)
      - Westinghouse, in appreciation, undated (Box 12)
      - Glass sculpture, undated (Box 13)
      - BPAA award, 1974 (Box 14)
      - Delta Dental, clock paperweight, undated (Box 14)
      - Medal on ribbon, inscribed Mendelssohn für Kunst/Ehrens zeichen #7, 1999 (Box 14)
      - Pittsburgh Junior Chamber of Commerce, award, 1954 (Box 14)
      - Stanley Marshall, Inc., embossing stamp, undated (Box 14)
      - BPAA Lifetime Achievement award, 1992 (Box 15)
      - World Federalist Association of Pittsburgh, Norman Cousins Award, 2000 (Box 16)
  - Photographs Subseries, 1970 and undated
    Includes photographs, proofs, and negatives.
    - American Market Association, 1970 (Box 17)
    - Marshall, undated, (2 folders) (Box 17)
    - Negatives, undated, (2 folders) (Box 17)
    - Portraits, undated (Box 17)
    - Proofs, undated, (3 folders) (Box 17)
    - Rosie's party, undated (Box 17)
    - United Way, undated (Box 17)
    - Other photographs, undated, (2 folders) (Box 17)
- Professional Files Series, 1944-2004 and undated, (6 boxes)
  Consists of invoices, legal documents, correspondence, writings, and sample forms and letters used by Marshall during his career with Lando, Inc., Marstellar, and Stanley C. Marshall, Inc.. Series is organized into 3 subseries: Office Files, Speeches and Presentations, and Writings.
  - Office Files Subseries, 1970-2004 and undated
    - Announcements, 1986 and undated (Box 18)
    - Biographical information, 1970, 1984, 2003 and undated (Box 18)
    - Correspondence
      - Jeff Perkins, 1999 (Box 18)
      - Lloyd Slater, 1980-2004 (Box 18)
      - Jeffrey Wray, 1991 (Box 18)
    - Directories, 2000 and undated (Box 18)
    - Forms, undated, (2 folders) (Box 18)
    - Incorporation papers
      - Stanley L. Marshall, Inc., 1979-1982 (Box 18)
      - USA Now, Inc., 1984-1985 (Box 18)
    - Invoices, 1994-2004 and undated (Box 18)
    - Jobs list, 1970s-2003, (2 folders) (Box 18)
    - Lando-Marstellar, 1970 and undated (Box 18)
    - Legal papers, 1994-1995, (2 folders) (Box 18)
    - Letters of reference, 2003-2004 (Box 19)
    - Marketing Marshall, 1994-1998 and undated (Box 19)
    - Sample letters, undated, (2 folders) (Box 19)
    - Workshop setup, undated (Box 19)
  - Speeches and Presentations Subseries, 1965-2003 and undated
    - Anecdotes, 1960s-2004 and undated, (8 folders) (Box 19)
    - Research, 1980-2004 and undated, (2 folders) (Box 20)
    - Speeches
      Includes speeches and presentations given by Marshall during his career. Arranged chronologically.
      - 1965-1995, (18 folders) (Box 20)
      - 1999-2003 and undated, (5 folders) (Box 21)
    - Slides
      - Communications strategy, undated (Box 21)
      - Graphs, undated (Box 21)
      - Partnership for Productivity, undated (Box 21)
      - Positioning, undated (Box 21)
      - Positioning-General, undated, (2 folders) (Box 21)
      - Positioning-Westinghouse, undated (Box 21)
      - Westinghouse lamp survey, undated (Box 21)
      - Wood, Joe undated (Box 21)
      - Untitled, undated, (1 of 9 folders) (Box 21)
      - Untitled, undated (continued), (2-9 of 9 folders) (Box 22)
  - Writings Subseries, 1944-2001
    - Case for Sound Research, 1974 (Box 23)
    - Manuals and other writings for General Electric, 1944 and undated, (3 folders) (Box 23)
    - Marketing Communication, 1965 (Box 23)
    - Marketing Education in Czechoslovakia, 1992 (Box 23)
    - Marketing In A Shell Shocked Economy, 2001 (Box 23)
    - Marketing: the key to competitiveness, undated (Box 23)
    - Positioning, 1975-1976 (Box 23)
    - Voting is Fun, shooting script, 1952 (Box 23)
- Audiovisual Materials Series, 1952-2000 and undated, (8 boxes)
  Consists of audio and visual copies of radio spots, interviews, and presentations by Marshall during his career.
  Digital audio files are available for some of the materials in this series (OR13, OR14, OR16, OR20, OR22, OR26, OR41, OR42, OR43). They are located at: S:\Processed\Marshall, Stanley\audio files. Consult Reference staff for assistance.
  Original and Production copies are closed to patron use.
  - Originals (CLOSED)
    - Videocassettes
      - OR1. 2000 ADDY Awards Hall of Fame, 2000. VHS. TRT: 10:00. (Box 24)
      - OR2. Conflict Resolution, 1995, May 17. VHS. TRT: 30:00. (Box 24)
      - OR3. Hands Across the Sea, PfP in Zimbabwe, 1988. U-Matic. TRT: 28:32. (Box 24)
      - OR4. Penn Tech, undated. VHS. TRT: 01:05. (Box 24)
      - OR5. Penn Tech, undated. U-Matic. TRT: 10:00. (Box 24)
      - OR6. PfP/I Video: We're on the Way, 1985 and undated. VHS. TRT: 13:50. (Box 24)
      - OR7. PfP/I Video: We're on the Way, 1985 and undated. Dub from master. VHS. TRT: 13:50. (Box 24)
      - OR8. Presentation at West Virginia University, 1981, May 2. VHS. TRT: 15:00. (Box 24)
      - OR9. Westinghouse Marketing Awards, undated. VHS. TRT: 10:00. (Box 24)
    - Film Reels (Box 25)
      - OR10. Lando Inc. Agency Film, undated. 1" videotape. (Box 25)
      - OR11. Lando Inc. Agency Film, undated. 16 mm film. (Box 25)
      - OR12. Voting is Fun, 1952. 16 mm film. (Box 25)
    - Reel-to-Reel Audio Tape (Box 25)
      - OR13. Friends Tape, undated. 7.5 IPS. (Box 25)
      - OR14. Master, undated. 7.5 IPS. (Box 25)
      - OR15. Penn Tech 101, Edited Radio Spots, 1980, Aug 8. 7.5 IPS. TRT: 04:00. (Box 25)
      - OR16. Penn Tech Institute, 1987, May. 7.5 IPS. TRT: 01:00. (Box 25)
      - OR17. Bertolo and Studeny/Richardson, 1993, May 20. 7.5 IPS. TRT: 11:00. (Box 25)
      - OR18. Bertolo and Studeny/Richardson, 1994, May 25. 7.5 IPS. TRT: 11:00. (Box 25)
      - OR19. Penn Tech: Career Quest 1991, 1991, April 11. 7.5 IPS. TRT: 00:30. (Box 25)
      - OR20. Penn Tech: Career Quest 1992, 1992, April 21. 7.5 IPS. TRT: 01:00. (Box 25)
      - OR21. Penn Tech: Five Cuts 1984, Oct. 3 and undated. 7.5 IPS. TRT: 03:00. (Box 25)
      - OR22. Penn Tech: High Tech, Hum Drum, Plug In, 1988, April 21. 7.5 IPS. TRT: 03:00. (Box 25)
      - OR23. Penn Tech: Interview the Industry, 1989, Mar. 16. 7.5 IPS. TRT: 01:00. (Box 25)
      - OR24. Penn Tech: Just When You Thought..., 1990, July 26. 7.5 IPS. TRT: 01:00. (Box 25)
      - OR25. Penn Tech: Yawn, 1988, Sept 6. 7.5 IPS. TRT: 01:00. (Box 25)
      - OR26. Tools of the Trade: Coping with Change, undated. (Box 25)
    - Audiocassettes (Box 26)
      - OR27. Burson Marstellar interview 1993, Mar. 5. Cassette. TRT: 10:00. (Box 26)
      - OR28. Career Quest Profiles, 1992. Cassette. TRT: 20:00. (Box 26)
      - OR29. Partnership for Productivity is People, undated. Cassette. TRT: 03:00. (Box 26)
      - OR30. Penn Tech Institute, 1987, May. Cassette. TRT: 01:00. (Box 26)
      - OR31. Penn Tech Institute, undated. Cassette. TRT: 03:00. (Box 26)
      - OR32. Penn Tech Institute, Bertolo and Studeny/Richardson 1994, May 25. Cassette. TRT: 10:00. (Box 26)
      - OR33. Penn Tech Career Quest, 1991. Cassette. TRT: 01:00. (Box 26)
      - OR34. Penn Tech Career Quest, 1992. Cassette. TRT: 02:00. (Box 26)
      - OR35. Five Cuts 1984, Oct. 3. Cassette. TRT: 03:00. (Box 26)
      - OR36. Game Show 1990, Mar. 22. Cassette. TRT: 01:00. (Box 26)
      - OR37. Interview The Industry 1989, Mar. 16. Cassette. TRT: 01:00. (Box 26)
      - OR38. Just When You Thought... 1990, July 26. Cassette. TRT: 01:00. (Box 26)
      - OR39. Plug Into the Possibilities, undated. Cassette. TRT: 05:00. (Box 26)
      - OR40. Yawn, undated. Cassette. TRT: 01:00. (Box 26)
    - Digital Audio Tape (Box 26)
      - OR41. Penn Tech Location Audio. Undated. R120 cassette. (Box 26)
    - Records (Box 27)
      - OR42. Jaycee Vote March with Robert Anderson and the Westinghouse Choir, 1952. 33 1/3 rpm. (Box 27)
      - OR43. Remember November, 1952, Sept. 17. 33 1/3 rpm. TRT: 30:00. (Box 27)
  - Production Master copies (not for reference use) (Box 28)
    - Video materials
      Format: BetacamSP. Created: 2007.
      - PC1-PC4, PC6, PC8-PC12 (Box 28)
    - Audio materials
      Format: Audio cassette and Compact Disc. Created: 2006-2007.
      - PC13, PC26a-PC26b, PC41 (Box 28)
      - PC27-PC40 (Box 29)
  - Use copies
    - UC1-UC13, UC26a-UC26b, UC41 (Box 30)
      Format: DVD. Created: 2007.
    - UC27-UC40 (Box 31)
      Format: Audio cassette. Created: 2006
- Oversize Materials Series, (1 box)
  Oversize materials include a hand drawn caricature of Stanley Marshall and various printed bulletins and flyers.
  - Oversize materials (Box 32)